export default Flashcards = {
  "-KdPHHMWCGadVmqB4heI" : {
    "back" : "There are *4 AC levels* in __Burgundy__\n\n- Regional ACs\n- Commune ACs\n- Single Vineyard __Premier Cru__ ACs\n- Single Vineyard __Grand Cru__ ACs\n\nUnlike Bordeaux, each individual *Premier Cru* or *Grand Cru* vineyard has their own AC.",
    "chapter" : "16",
    "front" : "List the hierarchy of __Burgundy__ appellations in order from bottom to top.",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "page" : "89",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-KdPIirar5fkRABJUc8t" : {
    "back" : "- __high acidity__ \n- __low alcohol__ \n- mainly produced in __Chablis__, a few villages in __Côte d'Or__, and __Côte Chalonnaise__ ",
    "chapter" : "16",
    "front" : "Describe __Bourgogne Aligoté AC__ \n_(5 points)_",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "page" : "89",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-KdPRkds2JO8g8nlWG_Y" : {
    "back" : "Approx. *1/3* of all wine production in __Burgundy__ is from __Commune ACs__ such as *Chablis* or *Gevrey-Chambertin*.",
    "chapter" : "16",
    "front" : "What percentage of __Burgundy__ wine production is by *communal* or *village* appellations?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "page" : "89",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-KdPTXowNztc-UsL6eAl" : {
    "back" : "There are over __600 Premiers Crus__ in __Burgundy__, spread between *Chablis*, *Côte d'Or*and *Côte Chalonnaise*. Premier Cru wines account for approx.__1/10th__ of wine production in Burgundy.",
    "chapter" : "16",
    "front" : "How many __Premiers Crus__ are there in __Burgundy__?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "page" : "89",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-KdUJrSY15Jm43dDb4RP" : {
    "back" : "__Burgundy__ has approx. 100 ACs, compared to approx. 60 ACs in __Bordeaux__, even though it has less than 1/3 of the area under vine compared to its western cousin.",
    "chapter" : "16",
    "front" : "How many ACs are there in __Burgundy__?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "page" : "89",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-KdUN-UV7tlBVcYSZZbo" : {
    "back" : "__Burgundy__\n- vineyard name attached to a specific plot of land, registered in each town hall\n- each commune with __Premier Cru__ and __Grand Cru__ vineyards have their own ACs\n- most vineyards have many owners, each with individual parcel of vines, producing wines in their individual style\n__Bordeaux__\n- a château name is a trademark, owners can increase size of the property by adding vineyard plots anywhere in the appellation\n- __Grand Cru__ and __Premier Cru__ are not part of the AC system\n- consistent workers and winemaker teams for all vines in a given château, therefore consistency in style",
    "chapter" : "16",
    "front" : "What are the fundamental differences between the __Bordeaux__ and __Burgundy__ AC structures?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "page" : "89",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-KdUPp2fr3DhMrMVCoN_" : {
    "back" : "BEAUNE\n*Grèves* \nAppellation Beaune Premier Cru Contrôlée\n\n*OR* \n\nBEAUNE\n*Grèves Premier Cru* \nAppellation Beaune Premier Cru Contrôlée",
    "chapter" : "16",
    "front" : "What are two different ways __Burgundy__ __Premier Cru__ wines can state their *Premier Cru* status on the label.",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "page" : "89",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-KdUR6Rvmj3gSYW2Egzu" : {
    "back" : "__Burgundy__ has perfected four technqiues now synonmous with premium __Chardonnay__ production around the world:\n1. barrel fermentation\n2. barrel aging (usually 6-9 months)\n3. malolactic fermentation\n4. use of lees during maturation",
    "chapter" : "16",
    "front" : "What are four key characteristics of __white Burgundy__ wine making?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "page" : "89",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-KdWR4U39SPcYM7FXXOz" : {
    "back" : "- northern __continental__ climate, with severe winters and hot summers\n- autumns are cool with frequent rainfall at harvest time\n- lower annual rainfall compared with Bordeaux (650mm vs 890mm)\n- __spring frosts__ may appear as late as May in __Chablis__ region\n- summer rains may cause __grey rot__ and localised __hailstorms__ ",
    "chapter" : "16",
    "front" : "Describe __Burgundy__'s climate and growing conditions. (5 points)",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "page" : "87",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-KdWSlR2fe_n-2aUFM_w" : {
    "back" : "There are two key soil types found in __Burgundy__ vineyards:\n- calcareous clayey - predominately __Chardonnay__ \n- limy marl - mainly __Pinot Noir__ \nHowever, growers tend to plant whatever sells - ie. *Chardonnay* has replaced *PinotNoir* in most of __Chassagne-Montrachet__ even though the soils are calcareous clay.",
    "chapter" : "16",
    "front" : "What kind of soils can be found in __Burgundy__ vineyards and what grape varieties are typically planted on these?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "page" : "87",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-KdWTyZVCNL8PxExv0qU" : {
    "back" : "Mid-slope sites in *Burgundy* catch deepest layer of slope-wash and act as sun-traps.\n\nThis is important to high quality *Burgundy* wines because both __Pinot Noir__ and __Chardonnay__ are sensitive to the subtle variations in *terroir*, such as steepness and direction of the slopes, depth, drainage, heat retention and mineral content of the soils.",
    "chapter" : "16",
    "front" : "The best sites in __Burgundy__ are found mid-slope. Why?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "page" : "87",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-KddZjEEoQcYyLdMu7fw" : {
    "back" : "Correct Answer: (D) West\n\nMain vineyards in __Burgundy__ lie on the eastern fringe of the __Massif__ Central, acting as its protective barrier.",
    "chapter" : "16",
    "front" : "The majority of __Burgundy__ vineyards are protected by the central __Massif__ mountains to its:\n\nA) North\nB) East\nC) South\nD) West",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "page" : "87",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-Kdd_jLwvhHMEjx5g9r5" : {
    "back" : "1. Pinot Noir\n2. Chardonnay\n3. Aligoté\n4. Gamay",
    "chapter" : "16",
    "front" : "What are the *4* main grape varieties grown in __Burgundy__?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "page" : "87",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-KddcyZGtvV9O6SyD_Jz" : {
    "back" : "- *red fruits* (cherry, raspberry, strawberry) when young\n- *vegetal*, *savoury* and *gamey* notes when mature\n- medium to high tannins\n- medium to high acidity\n- full bodied",
    "chapter" : "16",
    "front" : "Describe characteristics of a classic __Burgundy__ __Pinot Noir__ wine.",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "page" : "88",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-Kddenbm6C10k82mOf0P" : {
    "back" : "- __Chablis__ - lean, steely, high-acidity\n- __Côte d'Or__ - rich, ripe, creamy-buttery, complex and expressive\n- __Mâcon__ - full-bodied, ripe fruits",
    "chapter" : "16",
    "front" : "How does __Chardonnay__ wines from different regions across __Burgundy__ differ?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "page" : "88",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-Ke-KK0WSZG_kA9eUu6D" : {
    "back" : "__Aligoté__ accounts for about 5% of total vineyard area in __Burgundy__, __Gamay__ accounts for approximately 10% .\n\n__Gamay__ was historically grown throughout Burgundy, but now only contributes to *Bourgogne Grand Ordinaire* and *Bourgogne Passetoutgrains AC* wines and red wines in __Mâconnais__.",
    "chapter" : "16",
    "front" : "How much vine does __Aligoté__ and __Gamay__ account for in __Burgundy__?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "page" : "88",
    "status" : "new"
  },
  "-Ke-M9aFlgEIGbfzNTJZ" : {
    "back" : "Answer: (A)\n\n__Burgundy__ vines are one of the most densely planted in the world, at up to 12,000 per hectare.",
    "chapter" : "16",
    "front" : "Vines in __Burgundy__ are one of the ______Burgundy__ are one of the __ densely planted in the world.\n\n(A) most\n(B) more\n(C) sparely\n(D) least",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "page" : "88",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-Ke-NDVQ3Xu_QqyY3G_r" : {
    "back" : "Most vineyards in __Burgundy__ train their vines low along wires using the __single Guyot__ system.\n\nSome growers in __Hautes-Côte__ may use a higher-trained vines system.",
    "chapter" : "16",
    "front" : "What training methods are used in __Burgundy__?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "page" : "88",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-Ke2EbXJVmywxIRdzbGE" : {
    "back" : "__Alsace__ has a*cool continental* climate, although the summers are hot and sunny, and autumns are dry and longer than is typical for this climate. __Vosges__ mountains, to the west of Alsace shelds vineyards from westerly winds, making Alsace one of the driest regions in France. ",
    "chapter" : "18",
    "front" : "What is the climate of __Alsace__?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "page" : "97",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-Ke2VWL9ht2OILTZ7Zpd" : {
    "back" : "Cool autumns and cold winters in __Burgundy__ may cause fermentation to stop if the musts are not warmed.\n\nThis is a threat for even cool-fermented white wines in __Chablis__ where temperatures can fall low enough to cause a problem.",
    "chapter" : "16",
    "front" : "What impact does __Burgundy__'s cool climate have on wine making?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "page" : "88",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-Ke2XXrb2zh3aqab1fQs" : {
    "back" : "- cold-soaking musts before starting fermentation\n- traditional open vat fermentation with pumping over of the juice -- sometimes with punching down of the cap\n- destemming may occur, with some winemakers retaining a portion of stems to provide a source of tannins",
    "chapter" : "16",
    "front" : "Describe typical red wine making techniques in __Burgundy__.",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "page" : "88",
    "status" : "new"
  },
  "-Ke7lQ5EqG7W4ZJ9y-1b" : {
    "back" : "The __1er Cru__ designation represents wines blended together from various __Premier Cru__ vineyards within a village.",
    "chapter" : "16",
    "front" : "What does a __Burgundy__ __1er Cru__ on the label indicate? ie.\n\nBEAUNE 1er Cru\nAppellation Beaune Premier Cru Contrôlée",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "page" : "90",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-Ke7mZk7m2I016VSjJDC" : {
    "back" : "There are 33 *Grand Cru* vineyards in __Côte d'Or__ and 1 *GrandCru* site in__Chablis__ (spread over 7 adjoining plots of land).",
    "chapter" : "16",
    "front" : "How many __Grand Cru__ vineyards are there in __Burgundy__?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "page" : "90",
    "status" : "new"
  },
  "-Ke7pjT5p4qJcki1TRiC" : {
    "back" : "*Example:* \n\nCORTON-CHARLEMAGNE\nGrand Cru\nAppellation Corton-Charlemagne Contrôlée\n\n__Grand Cru__ labels can be identified by the fact that the vineyard name stands alone on the label. It is unnecessary to state which village they wine comes from.",
    "chapter" : "16",
    "front" : "Give an example of a __Burgundy__ __Grand Cru__ label.",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "page" : "90",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-Ke7rKqQ-igJ1_PJx31F" : {
    "back" : "Mayors of certain villages in __Burgundy__ added the name of their most famous vineyards to aid with the sale of their simple village wines, such as the*Grand Cru* vineyard of __Corton__ to the village of __Aloxe__ to make *Aloxe-Corton*.",
    "chapter" : "16",
    "front" : "What do __Côte d'Or__ commune names like*Aloxe-Corton* and*Nuits-Saint-George* signify?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "page" : "90",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-Ke7u1il9g85445relzr" : {
    "back" : "__Chablis__ appellation originally requires vineyards to lie on limestone overlaid with*Kimmeridgian clay*. The appellation now extends to vineyards on*Portlandian clay*.",
    "chapter" : "16",
    "front" : "What soil types qualify for __Chablis__ appellation status?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "page" : "90",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-Ke7v1crcyyAL-jqUNEa" : {
    "back" : "*Frost* is __Chablis__ growers' biggest challenge.\n\nBetter vineyards install aspersion sprinkler systems as a protective measure. Heaters and helicopters is also used to circulate air and dissipate frost pockets.",
    "chapter" : "16",
    "front" : "What is the biggest climate problem facing __Chablis__ growers? What methods are used to mitigate that problem?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "page" : "91",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-KeAl8gPQCTgWKaPtWI0" : {
    "back" : "__Alsace__ has a great variety of soils:\n\nThe slopes include granitic, limestone, sandstone, clay, loam and volcanic soils.\n\nThe plains are largely alluvial.",
    "chapter" : "18",
    "front" : "What kind of the soils are prevalent in __Alsace__?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "page" : "97",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-KeB1O-leyNh14tkL6ga" : {
    "back" : "In some ways the appellation system in Alsace is very simple: there are only two ACs for still wine. \n\nThe Alsace (or Win d'Alsace) AC was created as recently as 1962, and accounts for over 70 per cent of the wine producion of the region. Alsace wines have traditionally been varietally labelled although a small number of blends are also made. If a grape variety featureson the label, 100 per cnet of the grapes used must be from the named variety. The wines must be bottled in characteristic tall bottles called flutes d'Alsace.\n\nAlsace Grand Cru Ac was introduced in 1975. There are currently 51 vineyards with Grand Cru status. Must be produced from a single noble grape variety(Riesling, Muscat, Gewurztraminer or Pinto Gris). There are a couple of exceptions that permit blending or use of Sylvaner. Varieties must reach a higher level of sugar ripeness than grapes destined for Alsace.\n\nVendange Tardive (VT) late harvest wines from the four noble varieties. Wines can vary from dry to sweet and there can be some botrytis influence.\n\nSelection de Grains Nobles (SGN): grage permitted same as VT. Grapes are affected by noble rot and the wines will always be sweet.",
    "chapter" : "18",
    "front" : "What is the appellations and classifications for still wine?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "page" : "98",
    "status" : "new"
  },
  "-Ker6tCXwHYgtJs2o43P" : {
    "back" : "The seven __Chablis__ __Grand Cru__ AC vineyards all lie on one hillside across the river from the town of *Chablis*:\n1. Les Clos\n2. Vaudésir\n3. Valmur\n4. Les Preuses\n5. Bougros\n6. Blanchot\n7. Grenouilles",
    "chapter" : "16",
    "front" : "List all __Chablis Grand Cru AC__ vineyards.",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "page" : "91",
    "status" : "new"
  },
  "-Ker8V2wBl3pLqSZLoJW" : {
    "back" : "__Chablis AC__ - austere; green-plum/green-apple fruit; high acidity\n__Chablis Premier AC__ - riper fruit (lemon citrus); more body, softer and creamier texture compared to *Chablis AC*; stony or smoky minerality; high acidity\n__Chablis Grand Cru AC__ - integrated oak flavours; smoky comlex aromas; long finish; refreshing high acidity",
    "chapter" : "16",
    "front" : "How do wine characteristics differ between __Chablis__ appellation levels?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "page" : "91",
    "status" : "new"
  },
  "-KesvEl5giDeTkoTIisL" : {
    "back" : "__Côte d'Or__ vineyards lie in a narrow band on slopes facing east or southeast, benefiting from the morning sun and protection of the*Morvan* hills.\n\nThe *Côte* is split into north and south halves:\n- North: __Côtede Nuits__ \n- South: __Côte de Beaune__ ",
    "chapter" : "16",
    "front" : "Describe the geographic features of the __Côte d'Or__ region.",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "page" : "91",
    "status" : "new"
  },
  "-KesyFBApfbFYrAhVrZR" : {
    "back" : "Answer: (B) *limestone* and *marl* \n\nSoils in __Côte d'Or__ is a mix of *limestone* and *marl* (a calcium-rich clay). \n\n*Limestone* benefits grapes with nutrients that make them grow better and produce sweeter grapes. While *clay* soils tend to stay cooler and retains water, important factor for making full-bodied bold wines.",
    "chapter" : "16",
    "front" : "What is the predominant soil types in the __Côte d'Or__ region?\n\nA. *sandy clay* \nB. *limestone* and *marl* \nC. *silt clay* \nD. *slate* ",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "page" : "91",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-KesycQhP4Ng0BBvDDwj" : {
    "back" : "Predominantly __Guyot__",
    "chapter" : "16",
    "front" : "What pruning method is typically used in __Côte d'Or__?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "page" : "91",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-KeszU3kMdFB2UevvkwT" : {
    "back" : "All red *Grands Crus* (except __Corton__) are produced in__Côte de Nuits__.\n\nAll white *Grands Crus* (except __Musigny Blanc__) are produced in __Côte de Beaune__.",
    "chapter" : "16",
    "front" : "How are __Burgundy__ *Grands Crus* distributed in the __Côte d'Or__?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "page" : "91",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-Ket-Qpbm3wstMFlwNW2" : {
    "back" : "*Grand Crus* of __Gevrey Chambertin AC__:\n- __Chambertin AC__ \n- __Chambertin Clos de Bèze AC__ ",
    "chapter" : "16",
    "front" : "List the *Grand Crus* of __Gevrey Chambertin AC__.",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "page" : "92",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-Ket-kfy-fSD_XXwvlKE" : {
    "back" : "*Grand Crus* of __Vosne-Romanée AC__:\n- __Romanée-Conti AC__ \n- __La Tâche AC__ \n- __La Romanée AC__ ",
    "chapter" : "16",
    "front" : "List the *Grands Crus* of __Vosne-Romanée AC__.",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "page" : "92",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-Ket0W05h6Y57Dz-i3x_" : {
    "back" : "- __Gevrey Chambertin AC__ \n- __Vougeot AC__ \n- __Vosne-Romanée AC__ \n- __Nuits-Saint-Georges AC__ ",
    "chapter" : "16",
    "front" : "Name 4 of the most important villages in __Côte de Nuits__.",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "page" : "92",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-Ket1WdkW2nfFuwYrFO2" : {
    "back" : "18 villages produce wine in the hills behind the vineyards of the main Côte.\n\nThe vintage takes place approx. 1 week later than on the main Côte, many in a co-operative cellar in __Beaune__. These wines are lighter in body and less concentrated than wines from the main villages of __Côte de Nuits__.",
    "chapter" : "16",
    "front" : "How many villages produce wine under the regional appellation __Bourgogne Hautes-Côtes de Nuits AC__?\n\nWhat are the differences compared to the main __Côte de Nuits__ villages?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "page" : "92",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-Ket2lkRFAr1ZgkDUKLI" : {
    "back" : "The most important villages (and their *Grands Crus*) in __Côte de Beaune__ are:\n- __Aloxe-Corton AC__ (*Corton AC*, *Corton-Charlemagne AC*)\n- __Beaune AC__ \n- __Pommard AC__ \n- __Volnay AC__ \n- __Meursault AC__ \n- __Puligny-Montrachet AC__ (*Le MontrachetAC*)\n- __Chassagne-Montrachet AC__ (*Le Montrachet AC*)",
    "chapter" : "16",
    "front" : "Name 7 important villages in __Côte de Beaune__ (and their*Grands Crus*).",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "page" : "92",
    "status" : "active"
  },
  "-Kf-HowU_hjm16csnXR6" : {
    "back" : "Riesling, Gewurztraminer, Pinot Gris and Muscat can be used to make VT, SGN and Grand Cru. The other most important of these are Pinot Blanc, Pinot Noir and Sylvaner.",
    "chapter" : "18",
    "front" : "What is grape varieties can be labelled in Alsace?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "page" : "99",
    "status" : "new"
  },
  "-Kf-L_KKVwgqP5kmjl4g" : {
    "back" : "The wine of Alsace can be both high in alcohol (14+% abv is not uncommon) and still retain an element of sweetness. This is due to the long, sunny, dry summers and autumns, which are the ideal conditions for grapes to acquire high levels of sugar ripeness. This mans that the yeast will be overcome by the alcohol before all the sugar is fermented. The dry conditons also mean that passerillage is more common than botrytis, so it is this that gives the wines a dried fruit character rather than the honey and orange marmalade character fo botrytis.",
    "chapter" : "18",
    "front" : "What is production of off-dry and sweet still white wines in Alsace?\n",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "page" : "99",
    "status" : "new"
  },
  "-Kf-NKRAcpEd1PH6Hdh5" : {
    "back" : "In the Central vineyards the climate is cool continental whereas further downstream in Anjou and the Nantais the influence of the Atlantic Ocean can be felt as the climate becomes more maritime. Variations in the weather patterns from year to year can mean that vintages differ widely. ",
    "chapter" : "19",
    "front" : "What is climate of the Loire Valley?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "page" : "101",
    "status" : "new"
  },
  "-Kf-PU0WA5-Rc2TjWYU4" : {
    "back" : "Styles of Chenin Blanc produced vary with ripeness level: grapes with low sugar ripeness will go to sparking wine production, fully ripe grapes will be used for dry wines, and over ripe grapes will be used for weet wines.",
    "chapter" : "19",
    "front" : "What is the styles of Chenin Blanc in the Loire Valley?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "page" : "101",
    "status" : "new"
  },
  "-Kf-RlDdMUxF82nywBkj" : {
    "back" : "Melon Blanc",
    "chapter" : "19",
    "front" : "What is the variety referred to as Muscadet or Melon de Bourgogne in the Loire Valley?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "page" : "102",
    "status" : "new"
  },
  "-Kf-TsEy6EqyxOt7kuto" : {
    "back" : "This is a dry wine withe no more than 12% abv. Recent improvements in canopy management have improved the physiological ripeness of the grapes and increased levels of concentration in the finished wine. After fermentation, which will have taken place in inert vesels, the wine remains in old oak casks or stainless stell tanks in contact withe the lees (yeast sediment) until bottling the following spring. The wine is bottled straight from the storage vessel. It may be filtered when bottled. Such wines often have a slight sparkle and the lees contact increases the body of the wine and adds a yeasty complexity. ",
    "chapter" : "19",
    "front" : "What is the production of Muscadet Sevre et Maine Sur Lie?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "page" : "105",
    "status" : "new"
  },
  "-Kf-YxmPaXY6f5iSqs9-" : {
    "back" : "This is a dry, hight acidity style of wine. The vineyards are located on south and south west facing slopes. Even so the grapes do not reach the levels of flavour ripeness that can be achieved in bright sunshine of New Zealand. This, combined with slightly warmer fermentation temperatures, means that th wine has a restrained style that eschews overt fruitiness for gun smoke and flinty characteristics. Better vineyard management has meant that the wines no longer have overt herbaceous characteristics. The small scale of vineyard ownership, the limited are of the AC and the high demand for the wines means that they always command a premium. ",
    "chapter" : "19",
    "front" : "What is the production of White Sancerre?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "page" : "103",
    "status" : "new"
  },
  "-KfeZt1u7MGgmH5a7kQw" : {
    "back" : "Always white and made from Chenin Blanc. \nA full range of style: still, petillant (semi sparkling) and sparkling - from dry to, in finest years, lusiously sweet. \nWhen noble rot in the vineyards, the vintage here can be among the latest in France.",
    "chapter" : "19",
    "front" : "What kind of wine style of Vouvray?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "page" : "104",
    "status" : "new"
  },
  "-KfhhsX6LPcHpdf-0LwH" : {
    "back" : "Nantais: Muscadet, Msacadet Sevre et Maine sur Lie\nAnjou-Saumur: Anjou, Saumur, Coteaux du Layon, Savennieres\nTouraine: Touraine, Vouvary, Chinon, Bourgueil\nCentral Vineyards: Sancerre, Pouilly-Fume, Menetou-Salon",
    "chapter" : "19",
    "front" : "Please list the wine producting regions and key wines in the Loire Valley.",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "page" : "",
    "status" : "new"
  },
  "-Kfmj0WznoeDT2MqsR5k" : {
    "back" : "Sauvignon Blanc",
    "chapter" : "19",
    "front" : "What is the grape variety in Sancerre (White)?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "page" : "103",
    "status" : "new"
  },
  "-Kfmjmg-UzJ5pKgibsC5" : {
    "back" : "Chenin Blanc.",
    "chapter" : "19",
    "front" : "What kind of grape variety in Coteaux du Layon?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "page" : "105",
    "status" : "new"
  },
  "-Kfmqzy-u4gqo763M8jW" : {
    "back" : "This is a sweet wine made from grapes, some of which will have been affected by noble rot. The amount of rot will vary each year. The vineyards are located in the sheltered valley of the Layon - the best are om south facig slopes - which encourages high levels of ripeness and the onset of botrytis. Several pickings will be necessary. Grapes are pressed and juice will slowly ferment due to hight natural sugar levels. Fermentation will stop naturally when the alcohol reaches 12-14%, leavimg high levels of residual sugar making luscious sweet wines with high levels of balancing acidity. These with high levels of balancing acidity. These wines can mature in bottle for decades.",
    "chapter" : "19",
    "front" : "What is the production of Coteaux du Layon?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "page" : "105",
    "status" : "new"
  },
  "-KfrvTly8LizqEwxERJo" : {
    "back" : "Sanvennieres is in Anjou Saumur, lies on the north bank of the Loire. Air circulation around the well-exposed vineyards impedes the development of noble rot, but enables late harvested Chinen Blanc grapes to be used for full-bodied dry wines of exceptional complexity. ",
    "chapter" : "19",
    "front" : "What is the production of Sanvennieres?",
    "level" : "WSET3",
    "page" : "105",
    "status" : "new"
  }
}
